ZiMuZu
倾情奉献
翻译
草草
磁芯章鱼X
翻译
电脑团
吃冰棒
翻译
TL
时间轴
纸袋P  念念  今
电脑狂人
第四季
第七集
校对&总监
草草
后期
饿得慌
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
力量
速度
高度
质量
好奇心
勇气
创作者  监制人
卡梅伦·豪伊
重新设计
重新上线
我是卡梅伦  请留言
This is Cameron, leave a message.
卡梅  我是博斯
Hey, Cam, it's Bos.
如果你在接下来几小时内听到留言
Look, if you get this in the next few hours --
喂
Hello!
怎么  你接电话还挑人吗
What, are you screening your calls?
怎么会
No, I wasn't.
没事没事
No, that's all right, that's all right.
我很欣慰我还算可接的那类
I'm just glad I still rate a pick-up.
你当然算了
Of course you do.
是这样  这几个小时你有事吗
Listen, what are you doing the next few hours?
我  说不好  反正我就在这儿
I -- I don't know. I'm just here, you know...
我需要你中午来帕罗奥图找我
I need you to meet me in Palo Alto at noon.
出什么事了吗
Is everything okay?
没有  都挺好的  我就需要你帮个小忙
No, everything's fine. I just need a quick favor.
博斯  求求你别再要我去做那些...
Bos, please don't ask me to do something --
不是  跟工作没关系
Oh, no, it has nothing to do with work.
我需要你中午来汉密尔顿大街350号找我
I just need you to meet me at 350 Hamilton Avenue at noon.
能帮我这个忙吗
Can you do that for me?
什么事啊
What is it about?
非得今天吗
Does it have to be today?
好姑娘
That's my girl.
汉密尔顿350号
350 Hamilton.
别迟到
Don't be late.
好吧
Okay.
早上好
Good morning.
我的天
Holy shit.
早上好
Good morning.
你是不是有什么东西昨天就该给我了
Wasn't there something you were supposed to give me yesterday?
你是指什么
What do you mean?
你的生物考试
Your biology test.
昨天不是拿到成绩了吗
Weren't you getting that back yesterday?
是拿到了  我得了A
Yeah, I did. I got an "A."
那真是太好了
Well, that's terrific.
在哪呢
Where is it?
你想看吗
You want to see it?
是  拿来我看看
Yes. Yes, I would.
我说我得了A  我就是得了A
Well, if I say I got an "A," I got an "A."
这样的话  那我们可以商量
If that's true, then maybe we can talk
让你每周回彗星上几天班的事了
about you coming back to Comet a few days a week.
可我不想去
But I don't want to.
你说我可以在那里上班
You said that I would keep working there
只要我觉得好玩
as long as it was fun.
现在不好玩了
And it's not fun anymore.
她的发型你真不打算说两句吗
You're seriously not gonna say anything about the haircut?
你觉得我说了有用吗
Do you seriously think that that would help?
我的天
Holy shit!
我们需要证婚人
Well, we need witnesses.
既然她把她女儿叫来了
Since she brought her daughter...
你怎么不早告诉我
Why didn't you tell me?
因为我们不想大动干戈
Well, because we're not making a fuss.
可是我至少可以换正装来啊
Yeah, but I would have... dressed up.
这样就很好
You're perfect.
谢谢你能来
Thank you for coming.
快读读  然后
Read it and weep...
喜极而泣吧
with joy.
我不想表现得太沾沾自喜  因为
Now, I don't want to get too far ahead of myself because...
我这人就这样  不过
that's my nature, but...
流浪者正在碾压竞争对手
Rover is crushing the competition --
包括你前夫的公司
your ex's company included.
没别的意思
No disrespect.
我们可以叫它"彗星"
We can call it Comet.
他们输的可惨了
Well, they're getting walloped.
我们的流量非常惊人  是彗星的两倍呢
Our traffic is phenomenal. It's twice what Comet is seeing.
用户得到想要的结果一般需要多久
How long is it taking people to find what they're looking for?
平均每次访问35秒  最长1分20秒
Uh, 35 seconds a visit, down from a 1:20.
用户来来往往
Users in and out.
客户可高兴了  唐娜
Happy customers, Donna.
太好了
Terrific.
我听说你打算去休个应得的假
So, I hear that you're taking some well-earned vacation time.
你打算去哪
Where you going?
或者更重要的是
Or more importantly, uh...
你和谁去
who you going with?
我哪都不去  就在本地放松放松
I'm not going anywhere. Just a little local R&R.
挺好的
Good for you.
自己独处一下  是吗
A little me time, eh?
多谢你跟我通报情况
Thanks for keeping me in the loop.
没事
Yeah.
你多保重
You take care of yourself.
别人可不会照顾你
No one else will.
是吧
Am I right?
没错
I'm right.
我在搜什么
What am I looking for?
时间
Time.
是  我会收电邮
Yeah. I get e-mail.
我在图书馆里用电脑
I use the computer in the library.
你是说那个什么天才吗
You mean that Prodigy thing?
我在搜什么
What am I -- What am I looking for?
园艺用具
Landscaping supplies.
你怎么在家呢
What are you doing home?
办公室的空调到底还是坏了
A/C at the office finally went out.
修空调期间大家都在家上班
Everyone's working from home while they fix it.
你回家干什么来了
What are you doing home?
博斯结婚了
Bos got married.
什么
What?
是啊
Yeah.
他们今天上午临时决定的
They just decided to do it this morning.
看来他们终于把问题解决了
I guess they finally worked things out.
他们说是因为现实原因  不过我说不好
They said it was for practical reasons, but I don't know.
当他们在礼台上说着誓词
When they were up there saying their vows,
注视着对方的眼睛
looking in each other's eyes...
你不会也湿了眼眶了吧
Are you getting misty?
我没有  我只是替他们高兴
I'm not. I'm just happy for them.
好了  好了
All right, all right.
别给我压力了
Stop pressuring me.
我只希望他们以后生活美满
I just hope it works out for them.
比我们以前的糟糕关系要好
You know, better than it did for our sorry asses.
我的意思是
I mean...
和其他人谈的恋爱  不是现在这次
our other relationships, not this one.
我懂我懂
I get it, I get it, I get it.
你是不是很急
You're not in a rush, are you?
对  我想回去工作
Well, yes, I want to get back to work.
-新项目开始上轨道了  -我想给你看看
- The new project is starting to hum. - I want to show you some
我拍的一些视频
of the videos I've been shooting.
让我走吧  我一早上时间就这么没了
Oh, please. I lost a whole morning because of this.
公众对互联网的理解
The public perception of the Internet
-阿莱克莎明天要来  -非常让人吃惊
- Alexa's coming tomorrow, - is really surprising.
如果是博斯之外的人  我根本不会接电话
and I wouldn't even have picked up if it was anybody but Bos.
还有你
Or you.
我也会接你的电话
I would have picked up for you.
别  别  走吧
No. No. Go on, get out.
-从我家出去  -好
- Get out of my apartment. - Okay.
你家里没厕纸了
You're out of toilet paper.
也许我今晚会去你那儿
Maybe I'll come out there tonight.
你竟然要自愿去清风房车
You want to come out to the Airstream voluntarily?
我可能需要一些厕纸
I might need some toilet paper.
太好了  你可以见见大家
That's fantastic! You can meet everybody.
我走啦
Okay!
我花了好长时间才哄比莉从角落里出来
And then I had to spend hours coaxing Billie out of the corner.
等我终于让她动起来了
And when I finally get her to move,
宾就突然开始发疯似的到处乱蹦
Bing gets a wild hair and starts bouncing all over the walls.
看  现在看它们啊
Look! And now look at them.
成完美的小天使了
Perfect little angels.
过来  快来看
Hey, come here, come look.
我以为我们要去散步
I thought we were going for a hike.
我们是要去  我只是想对
We are, I just want to, um, make one...
碰撞检测稍做下微调
minor tweak to the collision detection.
两秒钟就好
It will take two seconds.
这里景色可真美
It sure is pretty out here.
老天  看看这个
Oh, my God. Look at this.
我们应该盖一栋房子
We should build a house.
做个漂亮的露天平台
Something with a nice deck.
比莉真是厉害
I mean, Billie is bad-ass.
不要特别大
Nothing major.
就几个房间
Just a couple rooms...
两个  或许三个
two, maybe three.
然后怎么  露台就立即撤退
But then, what, Gazebo just instantly retreats
除非有食物吗
unless there's food?
我们该在每个房间里都建壁炉
We should have a fireplace in every room --
连浴室也是
even the bathroom.
消防滑杆
Fire pole?
跳钢管舞管
Stripper pole.
任何种类的钢管
Any kind of pole.
我觉得我们散步的时机快过去了
I feel like our hiking window is slipping away.
很荣幸能在你工作的地方
It has been a pleasure to fall asleep
睡着和醒来
and wake up in your work space.
我发誓  只要两分钟
I swear to God, two minutes.
我知道你是真心这么想的
I know you believe that when you say it.
等等
Wait, wait.
我今晚能请你吃晚饭吗
Can I take you to dinner tonight?
怎么  你觉得愧疚了
Oh, you feeling guilty?
有一点
Yeah, a little.
拜托
Please?
我们进城去  可以睡在大床上
We'll go into town, we can sleep in the big bed.
这才像话
Ooh. Now you're talking.
我晚点打给你
I'll call you later.
祝我好运
Hey, wish me luck!
好运
Luck?
你要运气做什么
What the hell would you need that for?
天呐
Oh, my God!
到底有多短
How short are we talking?
反正...
Well, it's um...
非常短
it's pretty short.
就是比桃乐茜·哈米尔要短
Like, shorter than Dorothy Hamill's,
美国滑冰运动员
但没有马克·哈米尔那么短
but not as short as Mark Hamill's.
美国男演员  出演过《星球大战》
两者中间吧
Uh, somewhere mid-Hamill.
精灵短发吗
Well, is it pixie-ish?
是像奥黛丽·赫本那样还是...
Is it like Audrey Hepburn or...
米娅·法罗
Mia Farrow
均为美国女演员
唐娜  唐娜  唐娜  不是那种发型
Donna, Donna, Donna, it is not that kind of haircut.
好吧  不是时髦的  你不会喜欢的
Okay, it's not fashionable. You're not gonna like it.
她为什么要这么做  她的头发那么美
Why would she do that? She has such beautiful hair.
我觉得可能她是想理清头绪
Well, I think maybe she's trying to work some stuff out.
做出某种声明
You know, make some kind of statement.
所有15岁的女孩都应该待在一个岛上
All 15-year-old girls should be just put on an island
直到她们准备好进入社会
until they're ready for civilized society.
我觉得有些女孩就是比其他人更不好过些
I think some girls just struggle more than others.
得了吧  海莉没事的
Oh, come on. Haley's fine.
我只是想在你看见她前给你提个醒
I just wanted to give you a heads-up before you saw it.
很感谢你这周照看她们
I appreciate you taking them this week.
我真的需要一段不被打扰的时间
I really just needed some... uninterrupted time.
嗯
Yeah.
戒酒会怎么样
How are the meetings going?
我在无聊和惊恐之间来回切换
I toggle between boredom and horror.
有人分享了一个由麻醉剂引发了便秘的故事
Someone shared a story about narcotic-induced constipation
我再没法把那个画面从脑中抹去了
that I will never be able to un-hear.
我就盼着这一切结束
Yeah, I'll just be happy when it's all over.
还有一个可爱的丢脸的结局
And as a lovely humiliation coda...
我被踢出流浪者了
I got kicked off Rover.
闭嘴
Shut up.
怎么了
What happened?
就是那一切
Just everything.
卡梅  博斯  戴安
Cam, Bos, Diane --
真是一场完美的糟糕风暴
it was a perfect storm of awful.
我很抱歉
Well, I'm sorry.
至少我们现在不是直接竞争对手了
I mean, at least we're not direct competitors anymore.
等彗星打败流浪者时  我心里会好受很多
It'll make it a lot easier when Comet kicks Rover's ass.
是吗  你哪来的自信
Oh, yeah? What makes you think that's ever gonna happen?
我们进展不错
Well, we're doing pretty well.
准备进行大力市场推广
About to launch a big marketing push.
你知道你们的用户数量吗
Do you know what your user numbers are?
知道  我们一天有5万点击量
Yeah. We got 50,000 hits a day.
流浪者是它的两倍
Rover's doing twice that.
每个用户能在35秒内找到他们想找的
The average user finds what they're looking for in 35 seconds.
很厉害
That's impressive.
是很厉害
Yeah, it is.
但同时也暴露出了它的弱点
But it's also what makes it vulnerable.
怎么说
What do you mean?
我觉得这场战争的赢家
I'm not convinced this fight gets won
不会是搜索速度快的那个网站
by the site that keeps traffic moving.
而是能留住用户的那个
I think it might go to the one that keeps users around.
这很有道理
Look, it makes so much sense.
我们为什么要致力于成为速度最快的网站
Why are we working so hard to become the fastest site
而不去做
when we could become the...
最能留人的
the stickiest?
如果我们能留住用户
If we can keep users hanging around,
那就能留住广告商
then we can start locking in advertisers.
但我们网站的意义在于把用户传递到其他网站
But the whole point is to deliver them to other sites.
不  但我们仍能这样做
No, but we could still do that.
但我们的网站也可以是个的目的地
But it could also be a destination in itself.
据唐娜所说的  我们比起流浪者差远了
Look, a-according to Donna, we're not even close.
-唐娜说的  -是啊
- Donna? - Yeah.
跟她有什么关系
What does she have to do with anything?
没什么  她今早来了一趟  我们
Nothing. She stopped by this morning, and we got to --
不
No, no.
我们不能听从唐娜的商业建议
We're not taking business advice from Donna.
是好主意的话  谁说的又有什么关系
Who cares where it comes from if it's a good idea?
她是我们的直接竞争对手
She's our direct competition.
怎么能听她的
Why would we listen to what she has to say?
因为她是这场竞争中消息灵通的选手
Because she's a really well-informed player in the field.
我们不能被唐娜的话耽误
We're not gonna be derailed by Donna.
我们要继续执行这个市场推广计划
We're gonna move forward with this marketing plan,
我也很高兴他们
and I'm really excited about what they're --
既然都要重新设计网站了
What's the point in coming up with a marketing plan
为什么还要制定市场计划
when we're gonna end up redesigning the whole site?
因为我们不打算重新设计网站
Because we are not going to redesign the whole site.
抱歉打扰了
I'm really sorry to interrupt,
但我们外面冻死了
but we are freezing out there.
我不知道昨天那人做了什么
I don't know what that guy did yesterday,
我觉得他可能想低温冷藏我们
but I think he's trying to cryogenically preserve us.
流浪者的平均访问时间为30秒
The average visit to Rover takes 30 seconds, okay?
而我们网站远超过1分钟
Whereas the average visit to us takes well over a minute.
我不相信这个数据
I don't trust that data.
你太荒唐了
You're being ridiculous.
你是又和她睡了吗
Are you sleeping with her again?
我在和我前妻上床吗
Am I sleeping with my ex-wife?
是的
Yeah.
我们打得火热呢
We're going at it like rabbits.
而凯蒂...
And Katie...
她对此完全没有意见
she's cool with it.
你们接触太频繁了
Been spending a lot of time together.
远超平时
Much more than usual.
她是我孩子的母亲  我们经常见面
She's the mother of my children. We see each other.
我就不该告诉你这是她的主意
I shouldn't even have told you the idea came from her.
那样你就会觉得这主意棒极了
Then you would have thought it was a great idea.
但这确实是她出的  而我是不会接受一个
But it did come from her, and I'm not taking business advice
致力于让我公司失败的人的商业建议的
from someone who's goal is to dance on the carcass of my company.
别这样  她没那么坏
Okay, come on. She's not that bad.
再说  她都不是...
Besides, she's not even...
她...
Look, she's...
她现在处境变了  好吗
She's in a different place now, all right?
她有其他的事要考虑
She has other things to worry about.
更何况她女儿在这儿工作好吗
Besides, her daughter works here, for Christ's sake!
你真觉得她会想尽办法
You really think she's gonna go out of her way
去毁掉她女儿所在的公司吗
to try and destroy a company that her daughter works at?
但她女儿已经不在这里工作了
But her daughter doesn't work here anymore.
现在是下手的最好时机
Now is the perfect time for her to strike.
她又不是个忍者  乔
She's not a ninja, Joe.
我来修  我来修
I got it, I got it!
我的天
Oh, my.
恕我冒昧来访  只是...
I'm sorry to barge in. It's just...
戈登告诉了我  而我...
Gordon told me the news, and I...
快请进来
Please, come in.
我们不是要瞒着任何人
We weren't trying to keep it from anyone,
只是这一切都发生得太快了
it just all happened so quickly.
你不会是怀孕了吧
Are you pregnant?
亲爱的  唐娜来了
Honey, Donna's here.
她还带来了一个蒂芙尼的大礼盒
And she brought something massive from Tiffany's.
-只是个...  -你太客气了
- Oh, it's... - You shouldn't have.
什么
What?
我都不知道蒂芙尼有那么大的盒子
I didn't know Tiffany's made a box that big.
看看你  健康又快乐
Look at you -- all happy and healthy.
见到你真好
Good to see ya.
是啊  感觉很好
Yeah, feeling good.
可以再去吃顿饭了
Ready for another dinner.
不过得换个餐厅
Different restaurant, though.
我只是想来说声恭喜
I just wanted to say congratulations.
我真是太为你们高兴了
I'm... I'm so happy for you.
我们真的只是为了税才结婚的
Well, we really only did it for tax reasons.
是啊  鉴于我差点死了
Yeah, on account of me almost dying.
这我可说不好  你们毕竟交换了誓言
I don't know. You pledged your troths.
我觉得这很浪漫
I feel like that's romantic.
大家都这么说
Well, that's what people keep telling us.
亲爱的  我能单独和唐娜谈谈吗
Sweetheart, can I have a minute with Donna --
如果你有空的话
if you have time?
当然
Mm, sure.
来
Here.
天呐  这玩意好沉
Geez! This thing's heavier than hell.
就是个大酒杯
Oh, it's just -- it's a punch bowl, I --
大酒杯
Punch bowl.
亲爱的  我们家的大酒杯都放哪里
Oh, sweetheart, where do we keep our punch bowls?
-放餐具室  我回头处理  -好
- Put it in the pantry. I'll take care of it. - Okay.
直接放在黛安车后座上吧
Or you can just put it right in the back of Diana's car
让她拿去换件漂亮的首饰
so she can exchange it for a nice piece of jewelry.
那我能得到什么啊
What the hell do I get?
黛安啊
You get Diane.
说得对
Oh. Fair enough!
唐娜
Donna...
首先  我该向你道歉
first of all, I owe you an apology.
我...
I was...
在流浪者的事上挺粗暴的
rough about Rover.
不  不需要道歉
No, look, no apology necessary.
那个
It was a...
情况很复杂
complex situation.
都过去了
Water under the bridge.
我想告诉你
I wanted to let you know
我准备从执行合伙人的位置上退下来了
that I'm getting ready to step back as managing partner.
真的
Really?
我们是清楚明白地知道
We got the message loud and clear
人不会永生不死了
about not living forever.
如果我想好好陪伴我的新丈夫
And if I want to spend time with my new husband...
执行合伙人可不是兼职工作
managing partner is not a part-time job.
你打算什么时候退
When were you thinking about doing this?
尽快了
Soon-ish.
我想告诉你  如果你还想做这个
I wanted to let you know that if you still want the job...
我会支持你
I'll back you.
我...
I...
当然了
Of course.
我想
I do.
那就好
Good.
我不能直接钦点你
I mean, I can't just anoint you.
当然
No, of course.
但我还是有很重要的一票的
But I do have a pretty jumbo-sized vote.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们庆祝一下吧  香槟  琴酒
Should we celebrate? Some champagne, gin?
水就好
You know, just water would be great.
好吧
Okay.
抱歉  我知道这里有点乱
Sorry, I know it's a little insane in here, but...
没事  很好的
No, no, it's --- it's perfect.
我听到"林中房车"时都不知道会是怎样的
I didn't know what to expect when I heard "trailer in the woods."
嗯
Yeah.
我觉得我是走进了你的大脑
I feel like I just walked into your brain.
不  我大脑里才没这么整洁呢
Oh, no, my brain is not as tidy as this.
你想看看吗
Do you want to see?
-当然  -好
- Of course. - Okay.
这还都是基本的
So it's all still pretty basic,
但是  我在做的是
but what I've been trying to do
创造有鲜明个性的机器人
is create bots with distinct personalities
他们的选择会依
and whose choices change depending on --
所处环境而变
on the circumstances they're in.
-自学式人工智能  -没错
- Self-learning A.I. - Exactly.
所以不仅仅是玩家在操作游戏
So it's not just the player acting upon the game,
游戏自己也有变化
it's the game acting upon itself
玩家要努力跟上节奏
and then the player has to try and catch up.
这是宾和比莉
So this is Bing and Billie,
这是露台
and this is Gazebo.
我还有一堆  他们三个是主角
I have a bunch, but these are kind of the main three.
我是想创造一个
What I'm really trying to do is create a world
行为有对应后果的世界
in which actions have consequences, you know?
我在《朝圣者》里就是想这么做
I mean, I was trying to do that with Pilgrim, too,
但那个游戏看来是太...
but I guess that game was too...
孤独  太难了吧
solitary or hard or whatever.
但是  在这里  我觉得我创造了
But, um, here, I feel like I'm creating characters
有能力积累记忆
that have the ability to accrue memory and -- and -- and --
发展个人故事线  并随时间改变的人物
and develop a personal narrative and -- and change over time.
这都感觉很
And it's all just feeling really...
浸入式  很完整
immersive and complete.
-很不错  -嗯
- Really great. - Yeah.
我知道你肯定能做好  我并不意外
I mean, I was expecting great, so I'm not surprised.
你想看看我正在进行的一些部分吗
So do you want to see some of the more, um, in-progress work?
好啊
Sure.
要不我们出去走走
Or maybe we could go for a little hike,
再聊聊大局
talk more big-picture.
这外面好美
It's just so gorgeous out here.
好吧
Okay.
这不是你想要的吗
So it wasn't really what you were looking for?
不是
No, no. It's just...
我觉得有时候  你处于开阔的空间时
sometimes I think the ideas can get bigger
思维也会更加开阔
when the space around you does.
是啊
Yeah.
没错  那我们
Yes. Let's...
我一整天都想出去转转来着
I've been trying to get out for a hike all day.
我们出去吧
Let's -- Let's get out there.
我们可以叫人来
We can call a guy.
我叫过人了  他搞得更糟了
I already called a guy, he made it worse.
你不也是
So did you.
就是断路器坏了  我修得好
Look, it's a bad breaker. I can fix that.
没那么简单
It's more than a bad breaker.
你真不叫人来吗
You sure you don't want to call a guy?
拜托  这又不是高深的科学
You guys, this is not rocket science.
好吧
Okay.
谢谢给我们下午放假
Thanks for the afternoon off.
我没给你们放假
I didn't give you the afternoon off.
是要你们在家工作的
You're supposed to be working from home.
我说什么了
What did I say?
好吧  晚上见
All right, I'll see you tonight.
要我带点什么吗
Can I bring anything?
不用  我都准备了
Nope. Got all that covered.
你是个管事的人
You're a take-charge mama jama.
别炸掉什么
Try not to blow anything up.
我尽量
I'll try.
卡梅说唐娜上周去清风房车时
Cam said Donna was looking pretty rough
看上去很不好
when she came by the Airstream last week.
她有什么事吗
Is something going on with her?
卡梅伦说  她看上去不像她自己
Cameron said she didn't seem like herself.
卡梅八卦唐娜的事干什么
Why is Cam gossiping about Donna?
她担心
She was concerned.
我就是不信任她
Look, I just don't trust the woman.
我知道她是你的家人
I know she's your family,
我不该说什么
I'm not supposed to have an opinion about her,
但我不信任她
but I don't trust her.
海莉把头发剪了
Haley cut all of her hair off, okay?
剪得像男孩一样短
Short. Like a boy.
唐娜今早过来谈这事  但是
Donna came over this morning to talk about it, except...
短发
Well, short hair...
不代表什么啊
doesn't mean anything.
看来我那天不该冲你吼的
Well... apparently, I shouldn't have barked at you the other day.
听别人说一件你不知道的关于你孩子的事
But it's really tough hearing something about your kid
很让人不舒服
that you don't know about.
我能提个建议吗
Can I make one suggestion?
海莉现在一定不能觉得孤立无援
It's really important for Haley not to feel isolated right now.
这里非常适合她
This place is such a great fit for her.
我希望你能让她回来
I wish you'd let her come back.
我希望她回来
I want her to,
但她现在似乎非要恨我
but she seems pretty intent on hating me right now.
但她信任你
She trusts you, though.
她带你去了那间餐馆  不是吗
I mean, she took you to that restaurant, didn't she?
克拉克家
Clark residence.
海莉  我是乔·麦克米伦
Haley, Joe MacMillan.
我爸今天不在
Oh, my dad's not here today.
其实  我是找你的
Actually, I'm calling to speak to you.
我听说你不打算回彗星了
I hear you're not interested in coming back to Comet,
这让我很难过
and that really bums me out.
我也难过
It bums me out, too.
那就回来嘛
So come back.
我觉得那样不太好
I don't think that's a good idea.
怎么不好  我们需要你
Of course it is. We need you.
-我不知道  我...  -怎么了
- I don't know. I -- I just... - What?
我就是觉得我不该给我爸打工
I just don't think I should be working for my dad --
或是跟他共事  不管我们是怎么回事
or with him, or whatever that arrangement was.
没人比我更了解
Look, nobody knows better than me
跟你爸共事是多闹心的事了
how impossible working with your father is.
他脾气坏  没耐心  不知感恩
He's moody, impatient, ungrateful,
而且还是个出了名的百事通
and the know-it-all problem is legendary.
他就在旁边  是吧
He's standing right there, isn't he?
如果他就在旁边  我还会这么说吗
Would I be saying all this if he were standing right here?
会啊
Yeah.
好吧  那你就自问自答了
Okay, so you answered your own question.
你是这地方的一分子
You're part of this place.
我们需要你
And we need you.
我爸爸听到了吗
Did my dad hear that?
是的
Yes, he did.
他知道这是实话
And he knows it's true.
跟他说  我们今晚见
Tell him I'll see him tonight.
我就当你是答应了
I'm gonna take that as a yes
我会通知锅贴团队
and inform the Potstickers.
再说吧
We'll see.
她说  今晚见你
She'll see you tonight.
她语气是很高兴的
What, did she say that in a -- in a nice way,
还是威胁的
or like a threatening way?
高兴
Nice.
这下完全不出气了
Now the air's not coming out at all.
-没事的  -怎么会没事  乔
- It's fine. - It's not fine, Joe.
别误会  机器人科技是很赞
Don't get me wrong, the bot technology is impressive.
但暴风雪已经在做类似的东西了
But Blizzard is already doing something similar,
原点也是
and so is Origin.
我在这方面是完全有竞争力的
And I can totally compete in that arena.
但能不能开辟全新的领域呢
But what about an entirely different arena?
如果把你的软件用在火星表面呢
What if your software was used on the surface of Mars?
或是在人体血流里
Or in the human bloodstream?
如果用露台去防卫免疫系统呢
What if Gazebo could be used to defend the immune system?
你跟我一样清楚
You know just as well as I do
你在钻研的技术
the technology you're working on
不会只存在于游戏里
isn't going to just live inside a game.
嗯  这
Yeah, and that's...
说起来轻松
a very easy thing to say.
-但我做游戏很久了...  -不
- But I've been working on games for a long ti-- - No,
我并不是假装
I don't mean to pretend
我知道未来会是什么样
that I know what it's all gonna look like.
我问你个私人问题好吗
Can I ask you a personal question?
说吧
Yes.
你和唐娜·埃默森是怎么回事
What's the deal with you and Donna Emerson?
你们在门罗互联网战略会议似乎针锋相对
Things seemed pretty prickly at M.I.S.C.
我知道你们曾是"穆特尼"的合作伙伴
I know you two worked together on "Mutiny."
是啊
We did.
后来呢
So what happened?
我们对公司前景的看法不同
We didn't share the same vision for our company.
她是想把你推出你的安全区吗
Did she try to push you out of your comfort zone?
别担心  你是远见家
Don't worry. You're the visionary.
我只是来确保你有你需要的一切
I'm just here to make sure you have everything you need.
圈地已经结束了  这我承认
Well, the land grab is over. I'll give you that.
这样能很好地
Well, this is a great way
把弱点变成强项
of turning a weakness into a strength.
在我的采访过程中  我发现人们
You know, in my interviews, I'm finding that people
大都害怕网络
are mostly just scared of the Web.
他们怕会迷失于其中
They're afraid they'll get lost in it.
我知道  所以我们要给他们个庇护所
Yeah, I know. That's why we'll give them shelter.
最终不非得是
I mean, the end game doesn't have to be
推出一个软件包
to get wrapped up in some software package.
可以是把彗星变成网上的一个家园
It can be to make Comet a home on the Internet.
我们可以整合搜索最多的项目
What if we took an aggregate of the top searches.
科特·柯本死时  我们搜索量暴增
When Kurt Cobain died, we were flooded with searches.
如果当初我们
How amazing would it have been if...
在网页最上面写点什么  那多棒啊
if we had a little write-up about it on the top of the page.
是啊  那是很棒
Yeah. That would have been great.
这让用户和内容之间的共生关系
It makes possible a truly symbiotic relationship
成为了可能
between user and content.
大家对网站感兴趣
People will be interested in the site
是因为网站对他们感兴趣
because the site is interested in them.
是啊  没错  所以我才那么激动啊
Yes, exactly. This is what I was getting so excited about.
-我们可以有娱乐  新闻  -运动
- We could have entertainment, news... - Sports.
运动
...sports, uh...
股市
stock market.
没错  我们是要把人送去其他网站
And, yeah, sure, we would deliver people to other sites,
但他们总会回到我们这里
but they always come back to us.
没错
Yes!
你还要鼓捣多久
How much longer is this gonna take?
马上了
Just two more seconds.
你和卡梅  真是的  对时间完全没概念
You and Cam, I swear to God -- no sense of time.
瞧  谁需要叫人啊
See? Who needs a guy, huh?
-谁需要叫人啊  -好了吗
- Who needs a guy?! - So, it's good?
-乔·麦克米伦  -卡梅伦·豪伊
- Joe MacMillan. - Cameron Howe.
你今晚要带我去哪吃饭
So where are you taking me to dinner tonight?
那个啊
About that, um...
阿莱克莎请我去吃饭了  我也答应了
Alexa invited me out for dinner, and I kind of said yes.
好吧
Okay.
我真抱歉
Yeah, I'm really sorry.
我知道我说过会带你去吃饭的
I -- I know I said that I'd take you out, but...
没事
Oh, it's okay.
刚跟戈登开始研究一个点子
Just got started on something with Gordon,
我很乐意继续做下去
and I'm happy to stick with it.
真的吗  那好
Really? Okay.
因为她要我见个人
Because she wanted me to meet this guy
他在斯坦福大学研究人机互动
who is working in human-computer interaction at Stanford,
我还没反应过来  她就邀请我们一起去吃饭了
and then before I knew it, she invited us both to dinner.
听起来你们谈得很好
Sounds like things went well.
其实  不是  她...
Actually, no. She was..
对我给她看的不以为然
a little underwhelmed by what I showed her.
什么
What?
是啊
Yeah, she, um...
她应该知道我的编程不错  但是
I mean, I think she knew the programming was good, but...
但她觉得我的构思小了
she said I was thinking a little small.
你有多久没听人说过这话了
When was the last time you heard that?
我不知道
I don't know.
好久没有了
It's been a while.
今晚开心点
Have fun tonight.
谢谢
Thank you.
你真好
You're great.
而且
For the record...
我想过在这里建个房子
I have thought about building a place out here.
再见
Bye.
我觉得"重新上线"更好
I think "re-launch" would be better.
真是"大"改变啊
That's a substantive change.
挽救了整个项目
Saved the whole project.
"上线"就包含了设计
Well, "launch" subsumes design.
谁说的
Says who?
你不重新设计  就不能重新上线
You can't re-launch something without redesigning it.
当然可以
Of course you can.
好吧  是可以  但你不会的
Okay, you can... but you wouldn't.
开心了
Happy?
是的
Yes.
好吧
All right.
天呐  我哪蹭的这么脏
Aw, jeez! Where'd I get so dirty?
时间过得怎么这么快
Where did the time go?
我一小时后约了跟凯蒂吃饭
I gotta meet Katie in an hour for dinner.
我们明天再聊这个吧
Maybe we should get into this tomorrow?
好吧
Oh. Okay.
没问题
Not a problem.
反正我15分钟就得走了  还何必
Well, I mean, what's the point in launching into something,
聊"上"这个呢
you know, when I gotta get out of here in 15?
说的是
Of course.
今天干得很好
Great work today.
你今晚带她去哪
Where are you taking her tonight?
不去哪  姑娘们要去看电影
Uh, nowhere. The girls are going to the movies,
所以我们要待在家
so we're gonna stay home.
不错啊  这是个好点子
Nice. It's a really good idea.
嗯  我知道
Yeah. I know it is.
-唐娜  -乔
- Donna. - Joe.
出什么事了吗
Is something wrong?
不不
No. No.
一切都好
Everything's fine.
一切都好  就是...
Everything's great. I just, um...
我希望你能跟我说明白一件事
I was hoping you could give me some clarity on something.
好吧   我...
Um, okay, well, I...
我自己也没多少"明白"  但是
don't have a lot clarity to spare, but...
你想问什么
what's on your mind?
你为什么要把
Why would you give us
有潜在价值的市场调查告诉我们
potentially useful market research?
你说什么
I'm sorry, what?
今早  你见到了戈登
This morning, you saw Gordon.
他回来时因为你给他的信息乐得跳脚
He came back hopped up on some information that you gave him.
用户量  访问时长
User numbers, length of visits.
你为什么要跟我们说这些
Why would you share that with us?
我为什么不能说
Well, why wouldn't I?
因为你是我们的竞争对手
Because you're our direct competition.
好吧  首先  我已经不负责流浪者了
Okay, well, first of all, I'm not on Rover anymore,
我不是你的对手了
so I'm not your competition.
-其次  -你说什么呢
- And, secondly... - What are you talking about?
你才去找过卡梅伦
You just came over to get Cameron
让她转让算法
to sign away the algorithm.
没办法  乔
What can I tell you, Joe?
事情变化是很快的
Shit changes fast.
如果你已经不负责项目了  又怎么知道数据的
If you're off the project, how did you get those numbers?
那是真的吗
Are they even real?
乔·麦克米伦的自尊啊  又喷发了
The old Joe MacMillan ego, just, I mean, volcanic.
你怎么想的
What do you think? I... I...
我还有时间坐在那儿阴谋设计害你吗
I have time to just sit around and, what, plot against you?
反正不会是第一次了
Wouldn't be the first time.
我保证  我才不在乎你们公司
I promise you I don't give a shit about your company.
我之所以曾对它有过那么一丝关心
The only reason I ever even cared a little bit
是因为我女儿原本在那里工作
was 'cause my daughter worked there,
现在她都不做了
and now that's not even true.
所以  我真的都不去想它了
So, really, I give it just no thought at all.
其实  海莉还在我们这儿工作
Actually, Haley does still work there.
我今天下午跟她通话了
I spoke to her this afternoon.
是吗
Did you?
是啊
Yeah.
她是一个我非常在乎的人
She happens to be someone I care about very much.
她好幸运  因为她可缺
Oh, well, lucky her 'cause she's so bereft
-在乎她的人了  -唐娜  听着
- of people that care about her. - Donna, look!
戈登和我要开始钻研一个新想法了
Gordon and I are getting started on a new idea
而这个想法来自你无心之言
that sprang from a whiff of a hint
激发的灵光一现
of a nothing comment you made,
我只想确定  将心比心地说
and I just want to be sure... human to human...
你不是在谋划着想坑我们
that you're not planning to do something to screw us.
天呐  你以为我是什么样的人啊
Jesus Christ! What kind of person do you think I am?
你想把我赶出浏览器的项目
You tried to get me kicked off the browser project.
你偷了我们网络索引的点子
You stole our idea for the Web index,
这还只是在加州的事
and those are just the California crimes.
别逼我提德州的事
Don't get me started on Texas.
好吧  你知道吗  你是对的
Okay, you know what? You're right.
我不是一个值得信任的人
I am not a trustworthy person.
所以你最好还是别再来找我了
The best thing you can do is to leave me the hell alone.
相信我  那样我再高兴不过了
Believe me, nothing would make me happier.
-很不幸  -天呐  你赢了
- Unfortunately... - Jesus Christ, you won!
好吗  你赢了
Okay, you won!
你有海莉  有戈登  有卡梅
You got Haley and Gordon and Cam.
你有所有人  你还想从我这儿要什么
You got everybody. What more do you want from me?
天呐
Oh, my God!
真没断吗
Sure they're not broken?
我确定
I'm pretty sure.
跟我说实话  你为什么不负责流浪者了
Level with me. How come you're off Rover?
说来话长
Oh, it's a long story.
但是简单说
But the short version...
不是我的决定
it wasn't up to me.
抱歉我那么咄咄逼人
Sorry I got in your face.
但也不该这么对我
I don't think I deserved this.
你得知道我不是故意的
You have to know I didn't do that on purpose.
唐娜  行了
Donna, come on.
我当然知道
Of course I do.
我也绝不会去干扰彗星的  真的
And I would never do anything to interfere with Comet, really.
我不是那样的人
I'm not that person.
就算没有海莉
Even if Haley weren't there, I...
我不会的
I just, I wouldn't.
唐娜  我懂的
Donna, I get it.
被人那么想很难受
It hurts to be thought of in that way.
我也有过这经历
I've been there.
唐娜
Donna?
你怎么来了
What are you doing here?
你在干什么
What are you doing?
妈妈  妈妈
Mommy, Mommy?
*宝贝  别哭*
*Baby, no*
*不要哭*
*Don't you cry*
*宝贝  别哭*
*Baby, no*
*把眼泪擦干*
*Dry your eyes*
你确定
Are sure you can...
你可以开车吗
drive okay?
我没事
I'm fine.
那么
Well, uh...
我希望你们顺利
I hope it goes great...
不管是什么点子
whatever the idea is.
真心的
Really, I do.
你要怎么跟人说啊
And what are you gonna tell people?
打墙打的
Punched a wall.
因为我在流浪者上找不到我想找的
'Cause I couldn't find what I was looking for on Rover.
戈登
Gordon?
戈登  你在哪
Gordon, where are you?
你好  这里是戈登·克拉克
Hello, you've reached Gordon Clark.
我不在  请留言
I'm not here right now. Please leave a message.
是我啊
Hey, there, it's me.
你绝不会猜到  我刚刚客客气气地
You will never guess who I just spent
跟谁聊了一小时
a very civilized hour with.
起初不怎么客气  但是
I mean, I guess it didn't start out civilized, but...
唐娜
Donna?
戈登死了
Gordon's dead.
我是卡梅伦  请留言
This is Cameron. Leave a message.
卡梅
Cam?
是我
It's me.
该死
Damn it.
拜托
Come on.
该死
Damn.
约翰
John.
发生什么事了
What happened?
怎么了
What?